Guide to the George Champion Papers, 1925-2019, MS 3241
New-York Historical Society
George Champion papers
1925-2019
New-York Historical Society
Champion, George, 1904-1997
MS 3241
5.5 Linear feet in 5 boxes (4 record cartons and 1 flat box).
A collection documenting the life and career of banker George Champion (1904–1997), who served as president and then chairman of Chase Manhattan in the 1950s and 1960s. The collection includes correspondence with numerous politicians, among them U.S. presidents Richard Nixon and, notably, Dwight D. Eisenhower, with whom Champion maintained a close exchange spanning two decades. Champion's myriad other activities, such as his leadership of the Economic Development Council of New York, and his involvement with the Presbyterian Lay Committee to bring the Reverend Billy Graham's crusades to New York City, are chronicled in the collection's newspapers clippings, photographs, and ephemera. At the core of the collection are the drafts and scripts of Champion's many speeches, which he delivered throughout the country and internationally, and which he issued as pamphlets and periodical articles for wider dissemination.
Access Restrictions
This collection may be stored offsite. To arrange to consult it, please go to www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Carla Knobloch, 2023.
Arrangement
Before it was transferred to the New-York Historical Society, the collection was sorted in the alphabetical categories listed in the inventory of this finding aid. This arrangement has been preserved with some slight reordering and occasional expansion to accommodate objects not covered by the original categories, such as Champion's Dartmouth College sweater (Box 4), or the First Class Order of the Sacred Treasure insignia (Box 4, Enclosure 1). Maintaining this scheme has resulted in some degree of redundancy, particularly among the categories "Manuscripts," "Periodical articles—by George Champion," "Publications—by George Champion," and "Speeches," as some of Champion's writings and speeches, after their initial delivery, were printed in pamphlet form, or refashioned into magazine and newspaper articles. Similarly, researchers will find repeat correspondents appearing under the categories "Correspondence—Cabinet and other federal-level governmental," "Correspondence—Congressional," "Correspondence—Presidents, Vice-Presidents," and "Correspondence—Professional."
Biographical note
George Champion was born in Normal, Illinois on February 8, 1904 to George Champion (1871–1914) and Emily (Moore) Champion (1870–1945). [His paternal grandfather was also named George Champion (1840–1928).] He attended San Diego (California) High School and received a B.S. degree from Dartmouth College in 1926.
Champion was with the National Bank of Commerce, New York, from 1926 until 1929, when he joined the Equitable Trust Company. He was appointed Assistant Secretary of Equitable in 1930, and after Equitable and Chase National merged that year, he became an Assistant Cashier of Chase National.
In 1931 Champion left to become Vice President of Canal Bank and Trust Company, New Orleans. He returned to Chase National in 1933 as a Second Vice President in the southeastern district of the bank's national territorial organization. He was appointed Vice President in 1939 and became head of the southeastern district in 1942. He was named Senior Vice President in 1949.
Champion was appointed Chairman of the Personnel Relations Advisory Committee in 1950, Vice Chairman of the General Loan Committee in 1953, and Chairman of the Committee in 1954.
When Chase National Bank and the Bank of Manhattan Company merged on March 31, 1955, Champion was made an Executive Vice President. He was in charge of the United States Department, the bank's national territorial organization, from 1953 until January 1, 1957, when he became President. On January 1, 1961, he assumed the Chairmanship.
In the eight years during which he was Chairman of the Board, from 1961 through early 1969, Chase's assets grew from $9.3 billion to $19.3 billion and its deposits from $8.1 billion to $16.7 billion.
Champion retired from the Chairmanship of the Board of Directors of The Chase Manhattan Bank, N.A., New York, in March 1969. In that year he became Chairman and President of the Economic Development Council of New York City (EDC), a non-profit organization formed in 1965 "to help bring the capabilities of the business community to bear on vital urban problems."
During a career of some 40 years in banking, Champion won a reputation as one of the nation's foremost authorities on lending practices and money market operations. He also became an articulate spokesman for greater corporate involvement in social problems. A speech he delivered at Rutgers University in March 1966, which was later reprinted in the Reader's Digest, was widely heralded as a pioneering statement of the changing responsibilities of business in its new environment.
Champion was Chairman of the Contemporary Economics & Business Association and on the Board of Trustees of The Institute for Political Economy; the holder of Honorary Doctor of Law degrees from Millikin University, Grinnell College, and Pace College; and the recipient of Japan's Order of the Sacred Treasure, First Class.
He was a member of the Pilgrims of the United States, Psi Upsilon Fraternity, Casque and Gauntlet of Dartmouth, the August National Golf Club (Augusta, Georgia) and belonged to the Alfalfa Club (Washington, D.C.), the Links Club (New York), the Sky Club (New York), Round Hill Club, Inc. (Greenwich, Conn.), and Blind Brook Club (Port Chester, N.Y.).
George Champion died at home in Greenwich, Connecticut, on September 16, 1997. He and his wife, the former Eleanor Stevens, had two sons, George Jr. and Stevens, and a daughter, Emily Jean (Mrs. Carl W. Knobloch Jr.).
[This note is a reworking of a 1991 biographical summary of Champion found in the collection (Box 1, Folder 6). See also his New York Times obituary, "George Champion, 93, Head of Chase Manhattan in 1960's," Sep. 22, 1997.]
Scope and Contents
The George Champion Papers contain correspondence, draft and printed speeches, publications, newspaper clippings, photographs, oral history interview transcripts, and ephemera pertaining to Champion's forty-year career in banking, most notably with Chase Manhattan, and his philanthropic leanings. The collection includes letters between Champion and dozens of politicians, such as presidents Nixon, Ford, and George H. W. Bush, as well as the evangelist Reverend Billy Graham and the entertainer Bob Hope. Of particular note is the two-decades long, congenial correspondence between Champion and Dwight D. Eisenhower (frequently addressed as "My Dear General"), both before and after the latter's presidency (Box 1, Folder 12), and Champion's equally long exchange with Mamie Doud Eisenhower, much of which concerns fundraising for the establishment of Eisenhower College (Box 1, Folder 14). A note from Peggy Rockefeller (Box 1, Folder 10), wife of Champion's associate, David Rockefeller, praises Champion's decisive action during the so-called "Salad Oil scandal" of 1963, a fraudulent financial scheme committed by executives at Allied Crude Vegetable Oil Company that resulted in over $180 million in losses to major corporations; the scandal—and Champion's role in exposing it—is documented by newspaper clippings in the collection (Box 2, Folder 2). While the collection touches on Champion's myriad activities—such as his involvement with the Opportunities Industrialization Center (OIC) program (Box 2, Folder 5), the Economic Development Council of New York City (Box 2, Folder 19), and his continued interest in Dartmouth College's football team (Box 2, Folders 9 and 18)—at its core are the dozens of speeches he delivered to national and international venues (Box 3, Folder 10-14), which he often then issued as publications (Box 3, Folder 9) or periodical articles (Box 2, Folder 8) for wider dissemination of his philosophies.
Artifacts.; Award plaques.; Awards.; Certificates.; Decoration of honor.; Letters (correspondence); Newspaper clippings.; Oral histories (document genres); Publications (documents); Serials (publications); Speeches (documents); Tear sheets.; Bankers.; Banks and banking -- New York (State) -- New York.; Decorations of honor -- Japan.; Economic history -- 1945-1971.; Economic history -- 1971-1990.; Evangelicalism -- United States.; Bush, Barbara, 1925-2018 -- Correspondence.; Bush, George, 1924-2018 -- Correspondence.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969 -- Correspondence.; Eisenhower, Mamie Doud, 1896-1979 -- Correspondence.; Graham, Billy, 1918-2018 -- Correspondence.; Nixon, Pat, 1912-1993 -- Correspondence.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994 -- Correspondence.; Reagan, Ronald -- Correspondence.; Chase Manhattan Bank; Dartmouth College.; Economic Development Council of New York City.; Eisenhower College; Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge
- 1968 Billy Graham Crusade, 1965-1970, 1974 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Champion was long associated with the Reverend Billy Graham, and worked, as a board member of the Presbyterian Lay Committee, to bring Graham's crusade to New York City as early as 1957. See "Billy Graham & Co. to Invade New York," in the Pittsburgh Press, May 11, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1), and "Planning Committee for Billy Graham New York Crusade" (photograph caption) in The Presbyterian Layman, vol. 4, no. 5 (May 1970) (Box 2, Folder 7).
- Advocacy, 1979, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  • Sandra Stahman, Division of Curriculum and Instruction, and Lloyd M. Cooke, Economic Development Council of New York City, Inc., PROPED Project, Progess Report, July 15, 1979.
  • Memo for Record RE: The Citys Plan For a Co-Generation Loan Fund, July 23, 1979.
  • Robert Russell Sammon, Business Management Consultant to Public School System, report to Mayor Ed Koch, Nov. 28, 1979.
  • Issue: Reducing The City's Health Care Costs, undated.
  • Issue: Reducing Municipal Labor Costs, undated.
- Advisory Committees, 1979 July 26 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  Two-page summary of Mayor's Management Advisory Committee Breakfast Meeting, Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, New York, July 26, 1979.
- Awards and certificates, 1959-1976, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  • "Pair Parula Warblers by Dorothy Doughty [British sculptor] Presented to George Champion, President 1958-59, with the admiration and affection of the Association of Reserve City Bankers." With signed menu/program, Association of Reserve City Bankers 48th Annual Dinner (April 14, 1959) and schedule (April 13-15, 1959).
  • "Remarks of President Lyndon B. Johnson at the Alfalfa Club Dinner, Statler-Hilton Hotel, Washington, D.C." (Jan. 25, 1964).
  • [Tribute] "At a meeting of the Board of Directors of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York... the Deputy Chairman presented, and the Secretary read, the following tribute to George Champion (Jan. 7, 1965).
  • Program, "Pace College New York Civic Center Campus, Ground Breaking" (Dec. 19, 1966). Champion received an honorary Doctor of Human Letters. With "The Architecture of a Powerful Idea."
  • Man in Management Award of the Advisory Council of Pace College (Jan. 16, 1968). [2 copies of menu/program; 1 copy of guest list; 1 copy of Champion's speech "The Responsibilities of Leadership."]
  • First Class Order of the Sacred Treasure (Oct. 7, 1969). [See insignia (Box 4, Enclosure 1) and photographs (Box 2, Folder 10).]
  • National Football Foundation and Hall of Fame (1970, 1971, 1976).
  • Press release, "Citizens Budget Commission to Honor George Champion and William J. Ronan" (April 16, 1973).
  • [Menu/program] The New York Chapter, Association of the United States Army, Distinguished Service Award Luncheon, Guest of Honor, George Champion, Seventh Regiment Armory (Oct. 21, 1976).
  • [Certificate] City School District of the City of New York Cooperative Education Partner in Education. This is the Certify that the title of "Partner in Education" is hereby conferred upon George Champion... (undated).
  • Press release, "Chase Makes $100,000 Gift to Heart Surgery Group; Honors Former Chairman" (December 5, [year lacking]).
- Awards and certificates—American Legion, 1963 June 21 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 3)
  Award plaque: "The American Legion | Citation of Merit | Presented to | George Champion | This tribute of respect is presented in recognition of his under- | standing and untiring efforts in behalf of needy and | hospitalized veterans. | Kings County American Legion | June 21, 1963."
- Awards and certificates—First Class Order of the Sacred Treasure insignia, 1969 October 7 (Offsite-box 4, Enclosure 1)
  Presentation case holding insignia of the First Class Order of the Sacred Treasure presented to George Champion in 1969. The Order of the Sacred Treasure is a Japanese order established in 1888 by the Emperor Meiji. Originally awarded in eight classes (eighth being the lowest; first, the highest), the order is given to recipients—Japanese and international alike—in recognition of their outstanding public service in the fields of education, social welfare, medical care, and commissioned governmental work. Champion received the honor for his "meritorious services... rendered to Japan and... many contributions to [its] post-war economic and industrial development... and for the... promotion of Japanese-American friendship." The first class insignia consists of a ribbon or sash, a badge, and a lapel pin. Although photographs taken during the presentation show the lapel pin being affixed to Champion's suit, it is not present in the collection. Nor is the certificate mentioned in the ceremony program. [See documentation (Box 1, Folder 4) and photographs (Box 2, Folder 10), as well as en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Order_of_the_Sacred_Treasure.]
- Awards and certificates—Independent College Funds of America, Inc., 1965 February 28 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2)
  Award plaque: "Higher Education Award | of the Independent College Funds of America, Inc. | presented to | Mr. George Champion | For Distinguished Service to the Nation's | Private Colleges and Universities | Affiliated in the State and Regional Associations | February 28, 1965."
- Awards and certificates—Protestant Council of the City of New York, 1962 October 17 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  Oval medal, silver (stamped on edge "Medallucart Co. N.Y."), approximately 3.5 x 2.25 inches, in blue Tiffany & Co. pouch. Obverse bears a relief of a church and the legend "The Protestant Council of the City of New York | For Service to Church | and Community." Reverse reads "Distinguished | Service Award | To | George Champion | October 17, 1962 | In Recognition of | Outstanding Leadership | In Social and Spiritual | Service to Our City | and Nation."
- Biographical summaries, 1970-1976, 1991 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  Biographical summaries of George Champion dated
  • 1970 March
  • 1971 Dec.
  • 1972 Dec. [2 copies]
  • 1975 Jan.
  • 1975 April
  • 1976 March
  • 1976 June
  • 1991 April
- Casque and Gauntlet (Dartmouth College senior society), 1936-1937, 1964-1968 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  Correspondence and certificates.
- Congressional testimony, 1959, 1983 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  • Champion's address "The Challenge to the Dollar" quoted in "Exentsion of Remarks of Hon. John H. Ray of New York, in the House of Representatives, Monday, March 9, 1959" and printed in Congressional Record—Appendix, 1959.
  • Testimony of George Champion, Retired Chairman, The Chase Manhattan Bank, Before the Senate Banking Committee, Feb. 15, 1983.
  • Testimony of George Champion before the House Appropriations Committee Subcommittee on Foreign Operations, Sep. 20, 1983 [2 copies].
- Correspondence—Cabinet and other federal-level governmental, 1958-1984, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  Letters to and from
  • Appedorf, S. (1958 May 5, 12) + Goldman, Herman (1958 April 15)
  • Brennan, Peter J. (1974 July 2)
  • Burns, Arthur F. (1972 May 26, Oct. 25)
  • Bush, George H. W. (1971 Nov. 5)
  • Callaway, Howard H. (1973 May 29)
  • Camp, William B. (1969 March 10, 18)
  • Clements, Bill (1973 Feb. 2)
  • Connally, John B. (1971 Jan. 29)
  • Dent, Frederick B. (1973 Feb. 22)
  • Fisher, Carl W. (1969 Sep. 9)
  • Froehlke, Robert F. (1971 June 26)
  • Goldberg, Arthur J. (1962 Sep. 20)
  • Gordon, Lincoln (1966 March 8)
  • Ingersoll, Robert S. (1974 June 27)
  • Johnson, U. Alexis (1969 Oct. 17)
  • Kennedy, David M. (1969 Jan. 16, 30; 1970 Jan. 8, 16)
  • Kleindienst, Richard G. (1972 Feb. 21)
  • Korth, Fred (1962 Sep. 25, 27)
  • Laird, Melvin R. (1972 Feb. 12)
  • Marland, S. P. Jr. (1971 June 9; 1972 July 19, Aug. 22)
  • Middendorf, J. William II (1974 May 23)
  • Mitchell, John N. (1971 June 10)
  • Morton, Rogers C. B. (1974 Oct. 17)
  • Pannill, William P. (1971 June 28)
  • Peterson, Peter G. (1972 Aug. 15, Oct. 25, Nov. 3, 10)
  • Richardson, Elliot L. (1971 June 9; 1972 Nov. 20)
  • Rogers, William P. (1968, Dec. 12, 23; 1973 March 13)
  • Romney, George (1973 Nov. 13)
  • Rush, Kenneth (1972 Feb. 22)
  • Schultz, George P. (1970 July 14; 1971 June 2; 1973 March 30)
  • Simmons, Craig A. (1984 June 22, July 23)
  • Simon, William E. (1973 May 25; 1974 May 24, Nov. 4; 1975 April 30, June 26, Sep. 11, Oct. 20; 1976 March 18, June 14)
  • Stans, Maurice H. (1969 March 7, 19, Dec. 5; 1971 May 28; 1972 Jan. 13, 20)
  • Thompson, Jane (Mrs. Lewellyn) (1973 Feb. 9)
  • Uchida, Hiroshi (undated)
  • Volcker, Paul A. (1983 July 6; 1984 June 14)
  • Walker, Charls [sic] E. (1969 Dec. 10, 18)
  • Westmoreland, W. C. (1974 Feb. 3)
  • Wallich, Henry C. (1982 Feb. 19, March 1, 5, May 26)
- Correspondence—Champion, Eleanor, 1963-1981 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 10)
  Letters and notes to Eleanor Champion from
  • Bush, George H. W. (1972 May 15)
  • Cox, Patricia Nixon (1971 April 24)
  • Eisenhower, Mamie Doud (1975 Feb. 10)
  • Nixon, Pat (1965 Jan. [5]; 1967 Sep. [18]; 1971 March 20; 1972 March 17; 1981 Aug. [25])
  • Nixon, Richard (1972 May 19)
  • Rockefeller, Margaret "Peggy" (1963 Dec. 26)
- Correspondence—Congressional, 1959-1990, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 11)
  • Baker, Howard H. Jr. (1971 Dec. 3)
  • Boggs, Lindy (1975 June 24)
  • Brock, Bill (1973 April 25)
  • Buckley, James L. (1972 April 19; 1975 Aug. 13; 1976 Feb. 24)
  • Bush, George H. W. (1968 May 2, Aug. 13, 30, Sep. 4; 1969 Jan. 10–31, June 27; 1970 Feb. 26, Sep. 9, 17)
  • Bush, Prescott (1959 May 14, 19)
  • Byrnes, John W. (1972 Feb. 8)
  • Dirksen, Everett McKinley (1967 June 28, July 5, Aug. 2, 8; 1968 Oct. 18)
  • Dole, Bob (1973 Jan. 22)
  • Dominick, Peter H. (1973 April 27)
  • Dooley, Edwin B. (1961 March 2)
  • Ford, Gerald R. (1967 June 22, 26, July 27, Aug. 3, 10, Oct. 2; 1968 March 20, Aug. 9, 15)
  • Goldwater, Barry (1971 Dec. 28)
  • Goodell, Charles E. (1969 Nov. 12)
  • Holt, Joe (1959 Dec. 1, 4)
  • Javits, Jacob K. (1969 Nov. 12)
  • Latta, Delbert L. (1967 July 31, Aug. 3)
  • Leithead, Barry T. (1969 Nov. 7)
  • Long, Clarence D. (1983 Sep. 7, 21)
  • McCain, John (1990 Aug. 24)
  • McKinney, Stewart B. (undated)
  • Satterfield, David E. III (1971 April 27, May 3)
  • Taft, Robert Jr. (1971 June 21, Dec. 18; 1972 Feb. 21)
  • Thurmond, Strom (1972 Feb. 8, 14; April 7)
  • Tower, John (1972 Jan. 12)
  • Pages from Congressional Record—House (1969 Aug. 6, 7)
- Correspondence—Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1951-1953, 1958-1969 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 12)
  Letters to and from Dwight D. Eisenhower (1890-1969), written before, during, and after his presidency (1953-1961).
- Correspondence—Eisenhower, Dwight D. (copies), 1959-1968 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 13)
  Photocopies of selected letters to and from Dwight D. Eisenhower (1890-1969) from the previous folder.
- Correspondence—Eisenhower, Mamie Doud, 1962-1975 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 14)
  Letters to and from Mamie (Doud) Eisenhower (1896-1979), some concerning fundraising events for Eisenhower College.
- Correspondence—Eisenhower, Mamie Doud (copies), 1962-1971 (Offsite-box 1, Folder 15)
  Photocopies of selected letters to and from Mamie (Doud) Eisenhower (1896-1979) from the previous folder.
- Correspondence—Presidents, Vice-Presidents, 1966-1985, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 16)
  • Agnew, Spiro Theodore "Ted" (1971 June 4; 1972 Feb. 22)
  • Breeden, Richard C. [Deputy Counsel to the Vice President, George H. W. Bush] (1984 Feb. 8, 21, March 19)
  • Bush, Barbara ([1971?] Nov. 11)
  • Bush, George H. W. (1971 Nov. 10; 1982 Nov. 29, Dec. 22; 1983 Feb. 14, March 2; 1984 Jan. 31, Feb. 21, March 13)
  • "Coley" [Revolton B. Coley? in Ford White House] (1975 June 29)
  • Ehrlichman, John D. [Assistant to Nixon for Domestic Affairs] (1972 May 24)
  • Ford, Gerald R. (1975 June 5)
  • Harlow, Bryce N. [Counsellor to Nixon] (1973 July 6)
  • Humphrey, Hubert H. (1966 March 17, 19)
  • Johnson, Lyndon B. (1972 Oct. 13)
  • Laird, Melvin R. [Counsellor to Nixon Domestic Affairs] (1973 June 21, Nov. 1)
  • McDermott, Robert F. Jr. [Administrative Assistant to Peter M. Flanigan] (1972 Aug. 22)
  • Nixon, Richard M. (1970 July 13, Sep. 21; 1971 March 1, 17, April 5, 7, 12, Sep. 13; 1972 March 1, July 10, Oct. 30, Dec. 30; 1973 Jan. 9, 31, Feb. 22, May 23, June 4; 1974 Jan. 24, July 22)
  • Peterson, Peter G. [Assistant to Nixon for International Economic Affairs] (1972 Feb. 15)
  • Reagan, Ronald (1985 Jan. 4, July 16, 25)
  • Rustand, Warren S. [Appointments Secretary to Nixon] (1975 Jan. 28)
  • Ryan, Frederick J. Jr. [Deputy Assistant to Reagan] (1985 July 29)
  • Seidman, L. William [Assistant to Ford for Economic Affairs] (1976 Feb. 24)
  • Smith, Michael B. [Nixon Staff Assistant] (1971 Oct. 4)
  • Truman, Harry S. (1967 Aug. 24)
  • Vickerman, John C. [Staff Assistant to Nixon] (1973 June 8)
  • Woods, Rose Mary [Executive Assistant to Nixon] (1973 July 24)
- Correspondence—Professional, 1933-1990, undated (Offsite-box 1, Folder 17)
  • Berdon, A. W. (1936 April 8)
  • Blaik, Bob (1990 April 5, 12, 27)
  • Blaik, Earl H. (1983 June 8, 29, 30)
  • Borthwick, Anderson (1965 May 5, 17)
  • Boulware, Lemuel R. (1983 Sep. 28)
  • Bray, Thomas J. (1983 Oct. 18)
  • Breck, Henry C. (1968 Oct. 22, 30)
  • Busse, Paul ([1970 Aug.?])
  • Champion, George Jr. (1966 July 19)
  • Connally, John B. (1971 Jan. 20)
  • Connolly, William J. [transmitting Champion's address "Help Wanted: Efficient Management for New York City"] (1975 Oct. 2)
  • Driscoll, Robert S. (1983 Nov. 14)
  • Fifield, James W. Jr. (1968 April 15, 18) [includes pamphlet "What is Happening to the Churches?" by Dr. Howard E. Kershner]
  • Ford, Gerald R. (1989 May 26, 31, June 1)
  • Ford, Henry II (1973 March 2)
  • Frisby, Owen V. [transmitting article "Old Bankers Are Not Written Off," Forbes, July 1, 1976] (1976 June 23)
  • Galbreath, John W. (1969 July 11, Dec. 29)
  • Goldman, Leo R. (1969 Nov. 25, Dec. 3)
  • Goldwater, Barry (1966 Jan. 21, 27)
  • Graham, Billy (1964 Feb. 7, 13; 1966 Oct. 15, 20, Nov. 10; 1971 Nov. 9, Dec. 9, 17)
  • Gray, John D. (1970 Feb. 4, 9)
  • Grazier, Joseph, Paul Busse, and Oscar Dunn (1977 Jan. 13, 19)
  • Griggs, Leland (1957 March 6, 8, 13; 1963 Jan. 30, Feb. 1) [others lacking year]
  • Gruenther, Alfred M. (1970 Oct. 20, Nov. 15)
  • Hesburgh, Theodore (1986 Sep. 29)
  • Hirshon, Louis M. (1964 Oct. 16, 19, 20, 27, Nov. 3)
  • Hope, Bob (1970 Feb. 21; 1971 March 22, Dec. 27 [postcard]; 1972 Jan. 5, Feb. 8 [signed by secretary])
  • Hoxie, R. Gordon (1970 Jan. 19)
  • Johnston, D. W. [to George Champion Jr., transmitting Champion Sr.'s article "How to Put the Brakes on Big Government," Nashville Banner, June 15, 1966] (1966 June 16)
  • Kendall, Donald M. (1969 Oct. 31)